<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.0.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://rysarmstr.github.io/Data-Bites-Blog/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://rysarmstr.github.io/Data-Bites-Blog/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2020-04-26T17:31:51-05:00</updated><id>https://rysarmstr.github.io/Data-Bites-Blog/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Data Bites Blog</title><subtitle>Quick bites of my ongoing side projects and visualizations as I explore the world of data science and machine learning.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Getting Started</title><link href="https://rysarmstr.github.io/Data-Bites-Blog/miniconda/jupyter/vscode/streamlit/fastai/kaggle/coursera/2020/04/26/Getting-Started.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Getting Started" /><published>2020-04-26T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2020-04-26T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://rysarmstr.github.io/Data-Bites-Blog/miniconda/jupyter/vscode/streamlit/fastai/kaggle/coursera/2020/04/26/Getting-Started</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://rysarmstr.github.io/Data-Bites-Blog/miniconda/jupyter/vscode/streamlit/fastai/kaggle/coursera/2020/04/26/Getting-Started.html">&lt;!--
#################################################
### THIS FILE WAS AUTOGENERATED! DO NOT EDIT! ###
#################################################
# file to edit: _notebooks/2020-04-26-Getting-Started.ipynb
--&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;container&quot; id=&quot;notebook-container&quot;&gt;
        
    
    
&lt;div class=&quot;cell border-box-sizing code_cell rendered&quot;&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
    

&lt;div class=&quot;cell border-box-sizing text_cell rendered&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;inner_cell&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;text_cell_render border-box-sizing rendered_html&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;Intro&quot;&gt;Intro&lt;a class=&quot;anchor-link&quot; href=&quot;#Intro&quot;&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Hello, World! In my first real post I wanted to share some thoughts about resources for getting started in Python or data science. This has been nearly a 3 year process for me and could have been done much more effeciently - I'll point out a few of the ways I would do things differently if I were restarting today. Hopefully some of these tips can be helpful to others who are learning data science concepts at their own pace. I will try to keep this post updated with new resources as I find them. Keep in mind, as I'm learning as we go so these comments will no doubt be incomplete. If you've been through this process and have recommendations for things to improve or change please share them in the comments!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;cell border-box-sizing text_cell rendered&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;inner_cell&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;text_cell_render border-box-sizing rendered_html&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;Python-Install-and-Package-Management&quot;&gt;Python Install and Package Management&lt;a class=&quot;anchor-link&quot; href=&quot;#Python-Install-and-Package-Management&quot;&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;TL;DR: Read &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/dunder-data/anaconda-is-bloated-set-up-a-lean-robust-data-science-environment-with-miniconda-and-conda-forge-b48e1ac11646&quot;&gt;Ted Petrou's &quot;Anaconda is bloated.&quot;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First things first... 99% of what I write here will be about Python. As most beginners probably do, I started off by downloading &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.anaconda.com/&quot;&gt;Anaconda Navigator&lt;/a&gt; to keep things simple. The first mistake I made - against the &lt;a href=&quot;https://protostar.space/why-you-need-python-environments-and-how-to-manage-them-with-conda&quot;&gt;advice&lt;/a&gt; of many experienced python users - was to not using python environments from the beginning. As I learned about package management and different versions of Python there were a few instances where I ended up with a messy environment and decided I wanted to restart. The simplest thing to me &lt;em&gt;seemed&lt;/em&gt; to be (not in reality) a reinstall of Python. Long story short, I spent way more time fumbling my way through breaking and recreating my conda environments instead using that time to learn the actual packages. Eventually, I stumbled across &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/dunder-data/anaconda-is-bloated-set-up-a-lean-robust-data-science-environment-with-miniconda-and-conda-forge-b48e1ac11646&quot;&gt;Ted Petrou's &quot;Anaconda is bloated&quot;&lt;/a&gt;, which gives a fantastic overview of how to get a quick, effective data science set-up running in Python. Pairing this with a program like &lt;a href=&quot;https://code.visualstudio.com/&quot;&gt;Visual Studio Code&lt;/a&gt; can get you up and running quickly with the ability to start over easily when/if the time comes. Next let's talk a bit about interfaces.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;cell border-box-sizing text_cell rendered&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;inner_cell&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;text_cell_render border-box-sizing rendered_html&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;User-Interface-(IDE)-Selection&quot;&gt;User Interface (&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Integrated_development_environment&quot;&gt;IDE&lt;/a&gt;) Selection&lt;a class=&quot;anchor-link&quot; href=&quot;#User-Interface-(IDE)-Selection&quot;&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;TL;DR: If starting over today I would install &lt;a href=&quot;https://jupyter.org/&quot;&gt;Jupyter&lt;/a&gt; Notebooks, but use &lt;a href=&quot;https://code.visualstudio.com/&quot;&gt;Visual Studio Code&lt;/a&gt; as my daily interface. VS Code is a great text editor, but also gives you the power of IPython Notebooks and the freedom to experiment with other innovative interfaces like &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.streamlit.io/&quot;&gt;Streamlit&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course, you can always write Python code in a simple text editor and run your scripts from terminal, but modern IDEs offer a lot of built in efficiencies. When I started down the path of learning Python, the idea of not having an official IDE, like MATLAB or RStudio, made me a little squeamish. I jumped straight into &lt;a href=&quot;https://jupyter.org/&quot;&gt;Jupyter&lt;/a&gt; Notebooks for the simplicity and was ecstatic when I learned about Jupyter Labs, which takes the interactivity of Jupyter Notebooks a step closer to the full IDE experience. The &lt;a href=&quot;https://ipython.org/ipython-doc/1/interactive/notebook.html&quot;&gt;IPython Notebook&lt;/a&gt;, which is that basis for the Jupyter system is widely used across data science platforms like &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.kaggle.com/&quot;&gt;Kaggle&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.coursera.org/&quot;&gt;Coursera&lt;/a&gt;, which makes the transition from your machine to other platforms more seamless. The only thing I didn't like about the Jupyter environment was that I was locked into that interface.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What pushed me to try the oft-recommended &lt;a href=&quot;https://code.visualstudio.com/&quot;&gt;VSCode&lt;/a&gt; was the introduction of a new interactive interface called &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.streamlit.io/&quot;&gt;Streamlit&lt;/a&gt; (more on Streamlit in a bit). In order to try Streamlit I needed a text editor that was separate from Jupyter Notebooks. What I found in VSCode was a text editor that runs IPython Notebooks, has a built in terminal for package/environment management (or git), and of course efficiently edits text files. I'm still learning many of the creative editing shortcuts and I'm sure I am not using the extensions to their full capability, but VS Code has become my primary workspace.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lastly, I'll touch on &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.streamlit.io/&quot;&gt;Streamlit&lt;/a&gt;, a relatively new interface with a completely different take on interactive code. Streamlit runs the full code of your python script on every pass unlike IPython Notebooks which execute a single cell at a time. Streamlit allows compute-intensive functions to be cached so that they don't need to be re-run over and over. The shining feature that made me fall in love with Streamlit is its ability to add interactive features like buttons, sliders, dropdowns, or text input with a single line of code. These features make data exploration &lt;em&gt;much&lt;/em&gt; faster in Streamlit and also provide a framework to build simple apps for people looking to deploy ML algorithms quickly. This &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=B2iAodr0fOo&amp;amp;t=126s&quot;&gt;video&lt;/a&gt; from the co-founder and CEO gives a great introduction to the interface.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;cell border-box-sizing text_cell rendered&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;inner_cell&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;text_cell_render border-box-sizing rendered_html&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;Courses,-Podcasts,-and-Other-Resources&quot;&gt;Courses, Podcasts, and Other Resources&lt;a class=&quot;anchor-link&quot; href=&quot;#Courses,-Podcasts,-and-Other-Resources&quot;&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;TL;DR: Sites like &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.kaggle.com/&quot;&gt;Kaggle&lt;/a&gt; that incentivize project building are a great place to start. Fill in knowledge gaps with resources like courses, but don't fall into the trap of doing courses endlessly with no applied experience.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have spent the last 3 years or so learning python and then expanding into the world of machine learning and now deep learning. I can't say that it's been the most efficient process and I think an important take away is prioritizing efficiency when choosing your learning path. Not everyone has the same amount of time to dedicate. While a bootcamp might get you where you want to be in 6 months, it can be a large time (and monetary) commitment. &lt;a href=&quot;https://careerkarma.com/&quot;&gt;Career Karma&lt;/a&gt; is an interesting place to start if you are interested in bootcamps but don't know where to start. For the rest of us, Dan Becker (creator of Kaggle Learn) explains in &lt;a href=&quot;https://anchor.fm/chaitimedatascience/episodes/CEO-of-Decision-ai-Dan-Becker--What-does-it-take-to-become-a-Data-Scientist---Kaggle-Learn--Data-Science-Portfolio-eb631q/a-a1k35ik&quot;&gt;this episode of &quot;Chai Time Data Science&quot;&lt;/a&gt; that the first priority for anyone looking to move into a data science career should be building projects. Keeping that in mind, below you will find some of my favorite resources split out into those that are more conducive to building things quickly and others that are more helpful when you need to take a step back and just absorb some of the technical details. I'll leave it up to you to prioritize these in a way that works for you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Quick hitters:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sololearn.com/&quot;&gt;SoloLearn&lt;/a&gt; - Learn syntax for Python (don't spend too much time here!)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://ageo.co/kata&quot;&gt;Agile Geoscience Kata (for the geologically-inclined)&lt;/a&gt; - These small coding challenges are a great way to learn some python basics, especially if you are a geoscientist who works with subsurface data. Likely not as useful for others.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.kaggle.com/learn/overview&quot;&gt;Kaggle Learn&lt;/a&gt; - these courses have been specifically designed to get users into real use case examples of how machine learning is used to solve problems. The lessons are short, practical, and don't dwell on the details, but are enough to get you building. Coursera (see below) is a great alternative for more detailed learning.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://course.fast.ai/&quot;&gt;FastAI&lt;/a&gt; - FastAI is organized in a similar way to Kaggle Learn. Jeremy Howard gets you training deep neural networks within &lt;a href=&quot;https://course.fast.ai/videos/?lesson=1&quot;&gt;the first video lecture&lt;/a&gt; and provides insights along the way. Again, Coursera is an alternative reference if you eventually want to learn to build your own networks from scratch.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twimlai.com/&quot;&gt;TWIML Podcast&lt;/a&gt; - The TWIML AI podcast offers a large catalog of interviews with data scientists applying ML/DL. These may be difficult to follow along until you have a bit of experience, but the TWIML AI community also offers study groups and other resources that you may find useful.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.kaggle.com/&quot;&gt;Kaggle Competitions&lt;/a&gt; - As your skillset grows you can start applying what you are learning and discussing your results with the helpful community on Kaggle. My personal favorite is the yearly &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.kaggle.com/c/google-cloud-ncaa-march-madness-2020-division-1-mens-tournament&quot;&gt;March Madness&lt;/a&gt; competition, which was unfortunately cancelled due to the Covid-19 pandemic. Will try again next year!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;More Detailed/Traditional Learning&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://ocdevel.com/mlg&quot;&gt;Machine Learning Guide (Podcast)&lt;/a&gt; - Very high level overviews of data science and types of languages/algorithms. Similar content can be found on the web, but this may be a useful resource if you are a beginner looking for something to listen to on your commute or when you can't be on a computer.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.coursera.org/&quot;&gt;Coursera&lt;/a&gt; - If you need more detail than Kaggle Learn the applied lessons, there is a lot of content on Coursera. A few examples of commonly recommended courses:&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.coursera.org/specializations/python#courses&quot;&gt;Python for Everybody&lt;/a&gt; - The first few courses of this specialization will give you a crash course in python. It will provide more detail and active learning than something like SoloLearn, which is designed to be short and sweet.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.coursera.org/learn/machine-learning#syllabus&quot;&gt;Machine Learning&lt;/a&gt; great content as an introduction to the fundamentals of machine learning, but unfortunately taught in Octave or MATLAB. There is significant overlap between this course and the Deep Learning course below - you may actually try that first and see if you need to back track.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.coursera.org/specializations/deep-learning#courses&quot;&gt;Deep Learning&lt;/a&gt; - This course will introduce fundamental concepts related to building and training deep neural networks. Expect more theory and free-form coding than the FastAI course. As you get into coding in TensorFlow, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/kevinjliang/Duke-Tsinghua-MLSS-2017/blob/master/01B_TensorFlow_Fundamentals.ipynb&quot;&gt;this intro to TensorFlow fundamentals&lt;/a&gt; is also very useful document.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hopefully, these resources can be of help or at least get you moving in the right direction as you start your personal data science journey!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Introduction</title><link href="https://rysarmstr.github.io/Data-Bites-Blog/jupyter/2020/04/25/Introduction.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Introduction" /><published>2020-04-25T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2020-04-25T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://rysarmstr.github.io/Data-Bites-Blog/jupyter/2020/04/25/Introduction</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://rysarmstr.github.io/Data-Bites-Blog/jupyter/2020/04/25/Introduction.html">&lt;!--
#################################################
### THIS FILE WAS AUTOGENERATED! DO NOT EDIT! ###
#################################################
# file to edit: _notebooks/2020-04-25-Introduction.ipynb
--&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;container&quot; id=&quot;notebook-container&quot;&gt;
        
    
    
&lt;div class=&quot;cell border-box-sizing code_cell rendered&quot;&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
    

&lt;div class=&quot;cell border-box-sizing text_cell rendered&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;inner_cell&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;text_cell_render border-box-sizing rendered_html&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;Why-the-blog?&quot;&gt;Why the blog?&lt;a class=&quot;anchor-link&quot; href=&quot;#Why-the-blog?&quot;&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;I've spent my career studying geology and physics and have a passion for understanding the cause of natural phenomena. I have lots of experience looking at large data sets - seismic, gravity, magnetics, electromagnetics, and miscellaneous subsurface geologic data. Most of these projects have been done in MATLAB and ArcGIS.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More recently I've started honing data science skills to bring my intuitions about data exploration and data analysis into the world of machine learning and replicable data science using python frameworks and git. Until now, I haven't had a clear project or structured place to put my mini-projects. Now, this blog can serve as that space! Whether it's simple visualizations with geologic data or building neural networks to predict March Madness brackets - I will aim to document it here!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;Where-in-the-world?!&quot;&gt;Where in the world?!&lt;a class=&quot;anchor-link&quot; href=&quot;#Where-in-the-world?!&quot;&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
    
    
&lt;div class=&quot;cell border-box-sizing code_cell rendered&quot;&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;output_wrapper&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;output&quot;&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;output_area&quot;&gt;


&lt;div class=&quot;output_html rendered_html output_subarea output_execute_result&quot;&gt;

&lt;div id=&quot;altair-viz-c453bc367eff4b2291f0915850eea6a8&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;script type=&quot;text/javascript&quot;&gt;
  (function(spec, embedOpt){
    let outputDiv = document.currentScript.previousElementSibling;
    if (outputDiv.id !== &quot;altair-viz-c453bc367eff4b2291f0915850eea6a8&quot;) {
      outputDiv = document.getElementById(&quot;altair-viz-c453bc367eff4b2291f0915850eea6a8&quot;);
    }
    const paths = {
      &quot;vega&quot;: &quot;https://cdn.jsdelivr.net/npm//vega@5?noext&quot;,
      &quot;vega-lib&quot;: &quot;https://cdn.jsdelivr.net/npm//vega-lib?noext&quot;,
      &quot;vega-lite&quot;: &quot;https://cdn.jsdelivr.net/npm//vega-lite@4.8.1?noext&quot;,
      &quot;vega-embed&quot;: &quot;https://cdn.jsdelivr.net/npm//vega-embed@6?noext&quot;,
    };

    function loadScript(lib) {
      return new Promise(function(resolve, reject) {
        var s = document.createElement('script');
        s.src = paths[lib];
        s.async = true;
        s.onload = () =&gt; resolve(paths[lib]);
        s.onerror = () =&gt; reject(`Error loading script: ${paths[lib]}`);
        document.getElementsByTagName(&quot;head&quot;)[0].appendChild(s);
      });
    }

    function showError(err) {
      outputDiv.innerHTML = `&lt;div class=&quot;error&quot; style=&quot;color:red;&quot;&gt;${err}&lt;/div&gt;`;
      throw err;
    }

    function displayChart(vegaEmbed) {
      vegaEmbed(outputDiv, spec, embedOpt)
        .catch(err =&gt; showError(`Javascript Error: ${err.message}&lt;br&gt;This usually means there's a typo in your chart specification. See the javascript console for the full traceback.`));
    }

    if(typeof define === &quot;function&quot; &amp;&amp; define.amd) {
      requirejs.config({paths});
      require([&quot;vega-embed&quot;], displayChart, err =&gt; showError(`Error loading script: ${err.message}`));
    } else if (typeof vegaEmbed === &quot;function&quot;) {
      displayChart(vegaEmbed);
    } else {
      loadScript(&quot;vega&quot;)
        .then(() =&gt; loadScript(&quot;vega-lite&quot;))
        .then(() =&gt; loadScript(&quot;vega-embed&quot;))
        .catch(showError)
        .then(() =&gt; displayChart(vegaEmbed));
    }
  })({&quot;config&quot;: {&quot;view&quot;: {&quot;continuousWidth&quot;: 400, &quot;continuousHeight&quot;: 300, &quot;stroke&quot;: null}}, &quot;layer&quot;: [{&quot;data&quot;: {&quot;sphere&quot;: true}, &quot;mark&quot;: {&quot;type&quot;: &quot;geoshape&quot;, &quot;fill&quot;: &quot;rgb(220,220,220)&quot;}}, {&quot;data&quot;: {&quot;url&quot;: &quot;https://vega.github.io/vega-datasets/data/world-110m.json&quot;, &quot;format&quot;: {&quot;feature&quot;: &quot;countries&quot;, &quot;type&quot;: &quot;topojson&quot;}}, &quot;mark&quot;: {&quot;type&quot;: &quot;geoshape&quot;, &quot;fill&quot;: &quot;rgb(255,255,255)&quot;, &quot;stroke&quot;: &quot;rgb(220,220,220)&quot;}}, {&quot;data&quot;: {&quot;name&quot;: &quot;data-cec273aed151d8e1b6f86ca4e391833b&quot;}, &quot;mark&quot;: {&quot;type&quot;: &quot;circle&quot;, &quot;opacity&quot;: 1, &quot;size&quot;: 50}, &quot;encoding&quot;: {&quot;color&quot;: {&quot;type&quot;: &quot;nominal&quot;, &quot;field&quot;: &quot;Experience&quot;}, &quot;latitude&quot;: {&quot;field&quot;: &quot;Lat&quot;, &quot;type&quot;: &quot;quantitative&quot;}, &quot;longitude&quot;: {&quot;field&quot;: &quot;Long&quot;, &quot;type&quot;: &quot;quantitative&quot;}, &quot;opacity&quot;: {&quot;condition&quot;: {&quot;value&quot;: 0.95, &quot;selection&quot;: &quot;Select&quot;}, &quot;value&quot;: 0.15}, &quot;tooltip&quot;: [{&quot;type&quot;: &quot;nominal&quot;, &quot;field&quot;: &quot;Place&quot;}, {&quot;type&quot;: &quot;nominal&quot;, &quot;field&quot;: &quot;Experience&quot;}, {&quot;type&quot;: &quot;nominal&quot;, &quot;field&quot;: &quot;Description&quot;}]}, &quot;selection&quot;: {&quot;Select&quot;: {&quot;type&quot;: &quot;single&quot;, &quot;fields&quot;: [&quot;Experience&quot;], &quot;init&quot;: {&quot;Experience&quot;: &quot;Remote Study&quot;}, &quot;bind&quot;: {&quot;Experience&quot;: {&quot;input&quot;: &quot;select&quot;, &quot;options&quot;: [&quot;Remote Study&quot;, &quot;Field Data Collection&quot;, &quot;Education&quot;, &quot;Field Trip&quot;]}}}}}], &quot;height&quot;: 375, &quot;projection&quot;: {&quot;type&quot;: &quot;naturalEarth1&quot;}, &quot;width&quot;: 700, &quot;$schema&quot;: &quot;https://vega.github.io/schema/vega-lite/v4.8.1.json&quot;, &quot;datasets&quot;: {&quot;data-cec273aed151d8e1b6f86ca4e391833b&quot;: [{&quot;Place&quot;: &quot;Christchurch, New Zealand&quot;, &quot;Lat&quot;: -43.523672999999995, &quot;Long&quot;: 172.584118, &quot;Experience&quot;: &quot;Remote Study&quot;, &quot;Description&quot;: &quot;In 2011 I attended field camp in New Zealand and my study abroad in Christchurch was cut short by the 2011 Canterbury Earthquake. The following summer I studied the Canterbury region to identify repeating earthquakes within the aftershock sequence, which ultimately became my senior thesis at Colorado College.&quot;}, {&quot;Place&quot;: &quot;Eel River Critical Zone Observatory, CA&quot;, &quot;Lat&quot;: 39.718345, &quot;Long&quot;: -123.652625, &quot;Experience&quot;: &quot;Field Data Collection&quot;, &quot;Description&quot;: &quot;Geophysical data collection (Seismic refraction, electrical resistivity, and surface nuclear magnetic resonance).&quot;}, {&quot;Place&quot;: &quot;Snowy Range/Laramie Range, WY&quot;, &quot;Lat&quot;: 41.343634, &quot;Long&quot;: -106.50226, &quot;Experience&quot;: &quot;Field Data Collection&quot;, &quot;Description&quot;: &quot;My Master\u2019s thesis at the University of Wyoming was an integrated interpretation of the Snowy Range watershed, combining existing remote sensing data and airbone electromagnetic data (acquired by SkyTEM).&quot;}, {&quot;Place&quot;: &quot;Gulf of Mexico, U.S.&quot;, &quot;Lat&quot;: 27.040012, &quot;Long&quot;: -92.737999, &quot;Experience&quot;: &quot;Remote Study&quot;, &quot;Description&quot;: &quot;Various geophysical studies including seismic reflection data (pre-stack and stack) and well logs from the prospect scale to play scale across the GOM.&quot;}, {&quot;Place&quot;: &quot;Ghana&quot;, &quot;Lat&quot;: 4.140224, &quot;Long&quot;: -2.7299439999999997, &quot;Experience&quot;: &quot;Remote Study&quot;, &quot;Description&quot;: &quot;Stratigraphic interpretation of seismic reflection data for regional shallow hazard interpretation&quot;}, {&quot;Place&quot;: &quot;Porcupine Basin, Ireland&quot;, &quot;Lat&quot;: 50.91004, &quot;Long&quot;: -12.607474, &quot;Experience&quot;: &quot;Remote Study&quot;, &quot;Description&quot;: &quot;New Ventures - Basin play analysis&quot;}, {&quot;Place&quot;: &quot;Sergipe, Brazil&quot;, &quot;Lat&quot;: -11.16054, &quot;Long&quot;: -36.582305, &quot;Experience&quot;: &quot;Remote Study&quot;, &quot;Description&quot;: &quot;Seismic reflection interpretation&quot;}, {&quot;Place&quot;: &quot;French Guiana&quot;, &quot;Lat&quot;: 6.253583, &quot;Long&quot;: -51.223347, &quot;Experience&quot;: &quot;Remote Study&quot;, &quot;Description&quot;: &quot;New Ventures - Basin play analysis and prospect evaluation&quot;}, {&quot;Place&quot;: &quot;Sierra Leone&quot;, &quot;Lat&quot;: 6.832838000000001, &quot;Long&quot;: -12.358791, &quot;Experience&quot;: &quot;Remote Study&quot;, &quot;Description&quot;: &quot;New Ventures - Basin play analysis&quot;}, {&quot;Place&quot;: &quot;Offshore Newfoundland, CA&quot;, &quot;Lat&quot;: 56.149432, &quot;Long&quot;: -53.327567, &quot;Experience&quot;: &quot;Remote Study&quot;, &quot;Description&quot;: &quot;Prospect analysis and well planning&quot;}, {&quot;Place&quot;: &quot;South Africa&quot;, &quot;Lat&quot;: -35.402522999999995, &quot;Long&quot;: 17.756566, &quot;Experience&quot;: &quot;Remote Study&quot;, &quot;Description&quot;: &quot;New Ventures - Basin play analysis&quot;}, {&quot;Place&quot;: &quot;Mauritania&quot;, &quot;Lat&quot;: 17.840142999999998, &quot;Long&quot;: -17.204083999999998, &quot;Experience&quot;: &quot;Remote Study&quot;, &quot;Description&quot;: &quot;New Ventures - Basin play analysis and prospect evaluation&quot;}, {&quot;Place&quot;: &quot;Colorado College&quot;, &quot;Lat&quot;: 38.848814000000004, &quot;Long&quot;: -104.82287, &quot;Experience&quot;: &quot;Education&quot;, &quot;Description&quot;: &quot;B.A. in Geology and Physics 2013&quot;}, {&quot;Place&quot;: &quot;University of Wyoming&quot;, &quot;Lat&quot;: 41.314515, &quot;Long&quot;: -105.083647, &quot;Experience&quot;: &quot;Education&quot;, &quot;Description&quot;: &quot;M.S. in Geophysics 2015&quot;}, {&quot;Place&quot;: &quot;La Jolla, CA&quot;, &quot;Lat&quot;: 32.844702000000005, &quot;Long&quot;: -117.279075, &quot;Experience&quot;: &quot;Field Trip&quot;, &quot;Description&quot;: &quot;Stratigraphic sequences of deep water turbidites&quot;}, {&quot;Place&quot;: &quot;New Zealand&quot;, &quot;Lat&quot;: -39.282927, &quot;Long&quot;: 175.567631, &quot;Experience&quot;: &quot;Field Trip&quot;, &quot;Description&quot;: &quot;Frontiers Abroad field camp around the North and South Island\u2019s of New Zealand&quot;}, {&quot;Place&quot;: &quot;Utah&quot;, &quot;Lat&quot;: 37.426002000000004, &quot;Long&quot;: -110.980594, &quot;Experience&quot;: &quot;Field Trip&quot;, &quot;Description&quot;: &quot;Various field trips related to salt basins, stratigraphy, and source rocks.&quot;}, {&quot;Place&quot;: &quot;Rio Grande Rift, CO/NM&quot;, &quot;Lat&quot;: 37.261514, &quot;Long&quot;: -105.76544399999999, &quot;Experience&quot;: &quot;Field Trip&quot;, &quot;Description&quot;: &quot;Rio Grande Rift and plate tectonics&quot;}, {&quot;Place&quot;: &quot;Death Valley, CA&quot;, &quot;Lat&quot;: 36.464563, &quot;Long&quot;: -117.01251599999999, &quot;Experience&quot;: &quot;Field Trip&quot;, &quot;Description&quot;: &quot;Death Valley rift tectonics and structure field trip&quot;}, {&quot;Place&quot;: &quot;Washington State, CA&quot;, &quot;Lat&quot;: 47.631513, &quot;Long&quot;: -122.52166799999999, &quot;Experience&quot;: &quot;Field Trip&quot;, &quot;Description&quot;: &quot;Regional geology of Washington state&quot;}, {&quot;Place&quot;: &quot;Yellowstone, WY&quot;, &quot;Lat&quot;: 44.3413, &quot;Long&quot;: -110.40563600000002, &quot;Experience&quot;: &quot;Field Trip&quot;, &quot;Description&quot;: &quot;Volcanics and structural geology&quot;}, {&quot;Place&quot;: &quot;Hot Springs, AR&quot;, &quot;Lat&quot;: 34.510708, &quot;Long&quot;: -93.04945699999999, &quot;Experience&quot;: &quot;Field Trip&quot;, &quot;Description&quot;: &quot;Sedimentology and stratigraphy of the Jack Fork Group&quot;}]}}, {&quot;mode&quot;: &quot;vega-lite&quot;});
&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
    

&lt;div class=&quot;cell border-box-sizing text_cell rendered&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;inner_cell&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;text_cell_render border-box-sizing rendered_html&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am currently a Gulf of Mexico exploration geophysicist for Hess Corporation in Houston, TX. I spend most of my time intepreting subsurface data and following seismic data reprocessing projects, but my past experiences have been much more varied. Below are a few of my past roles and experiences:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Past Experiences at Hess&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Building workflows for cataloging well-based seismic amplitude analysis at a regional scale - Gulf of Mexico, USA&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Stratigraphic mapping of regional shallow hazards - Tano Basin, Ghana&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Data visualization using Spotfire for a geochemistry database&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Basin Scale Play Evaluation for New Ventures - Atlantic Margins (Ireland, Brazil, Sierra Leone, South Africa, Mauritania, Senegal)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Prospect analysis and well planning - Offshore Newfoundland, CA&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reserseach Assistant - University of Wyoming&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Processing and interpretation of airborne electromagnetic survey - Snowy Range, WY&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Geophysical data collection (Seismic refraction, ERT, GPR, Magnetics, NMR) - WY and CA&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.iris.edu/hq/&quot;&gt;IRIS&lt;/a&gt; internship and eventual &lt;a href=&quot;https://digitalccbeta.coloradocollege.edu/pid/coccc:8121&quot;&gt;senior thesis&lt;/a&gt; on repeating earthquakes near Christchurch, New Zealand - Research at University of Wisconsin - Madison (thesis at Colorado College)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"></summary></entry></feed>